if you're a beginner to final cut pro 10
and you just do not know where to start
then this
is the perfect video for you i'm going
to show you how to take your footage off
your sd card or your phone and get it
onto your computer so that you can start
editing in final cut pro i'll teach you
how to stay organized and back up your
footage so that you never
lose anything important we'll also take
a look at the software and show you
around a bit so that when you start
editing
things are a bit more familiar and it's
a lot easier for you
you got to just press record hey guys my
name is normal with think media now
let's get right into this video now
before we even open up
final cut pro we do want to get our
footage whether that's on an sd card or
your phone
onto your computer so if you do have an
sd card
which looks like this you can plug that
into your computer
if your computer does not have an sd
card slot you can get an adapter we'll
have links for all these resources
in the description down below if you
have something like an iphone you can
actually airdrop it straight onto
your computer but you want to stay
organized so we're going to create a
folder on our desktop right here and i
actually have an sd card so this is my
sd card right here
i'll go into dcim and right here i have
some fuji footage
over here and just on my computer in my
movies folder i have think media videos
and i'm going to create a brand new
folder and we're gonna title this
uh final cut tutorial obviously for your
name you can name it whatever you'd like
uh that's easy to remember for the
project that you are working on
at this point we are going to select the
footage from our sd card which is over
here
i'm going to hold down shift after
selecting the top one and then select
the bottom one i'm going to drag that
over my final cut tutorial up here we
get this loading bar it's going to take
a few minutes to copy all our videos
over
onto our folder and then up next we are
going to
import that into final cut pro x the
reason i like to do this is kind of as
a backup so having the actual videos on
your computer
if something does go wrong and you
happen to lose your footage somehow
or you accidentally delete it then you
still have those original files on the
sd card and you can easily re-link those
inside the software so that's why i like
to always copy my footage onto
my computer first or you can use
something like a samsung t5
hard drive and you can edit straight off
of that but to keep things simple we're
just going to keep everything on the
computer
all right now that our videos are in our
folder we can actually open up this
folder make sure they're all in there
and what we can do too is make a new
folder and we can title this
videos and that way maybe when we
download some music and we want to add
that into our project we can always come
back to this folder we can make a new
folder called music
we can put all our music in here we can
do the same for images
maybe one for b-roll and a-roll if you
want to separate
your videos but this keeps everything
organized and that's what i do for my
projects
is i have different folders for all my
assets in the video so having those
folders really keeps me organized if i
ever go back to that project i don't
have
missing files so it's definitely
something you want to get in the habit
of doing now let's open up final cut pro
x
if you just downloaded it or installed
it or if you want to you can get a 90
day free trial we'll have a link in the
description when you first
install it you're going to want to go
down here and open up your launchpad on
your launchpad you are going to see your
app somewhere over here mine is on the
second page right here
and if you want to bring it down here
you just can drag it and this will put
it
inside of this little dock so that way
it's easy to access you can just go down
here and hit final cut pro and double
tap it and this is going to open up the
software now this is what it looks like
when you first
open it up and the first step to do to
import our footage is create
a library on this left side over here we
see that this is where a library would
go but since we don't have one we're
gonna go to file
we're gonna go to new and we're gonna
select library for the name i just like
to leave it as the same name as my
project so i'll just do you know final
cut tutorial it doesn't even have to be
the same it doesn't really matter
but to keep organized we are gonna place
it in the same folder so in movies and
think media videos i'm gonna add final
cut tutorial and i'm just going to put
it inside of this folder we'll hit
save and now if i go back to that folder
you are going to see that we have a
library
right here this library is going to hold
everything so if you ever need to get
back in there and edit you can actually
go right in here you can double click
this and it's going to open up
that library with the videos that you
have in there right here is where you
have an event and this is where you're
going to upload
some of that footage we click on it once
we can rename it and we are just going
to call this
fuji footage and that way i can upload
all my fuji footage in here and it's
really easy to know
that this is where my fuji footage is
with that selected we're going to hit
import media and this is going to open
up our media
import tab i'm going to find my footage
by going to nolan mold
then going to movies and then think
media videos
right here is my final cut tutorial and
if i select that it's actually just
going to import everything
inside of this folder obviously the
library can't be imported but i do have
my video in there
so i'm just going to select that and
then over here we have a lot of options
on this right hand side we can see right
here that it's going to add
to our existing event fuji footage which
we just made
and then as far as files go you want to
leave
files in place if you copy to the
library your library is going to get
very large and i actually just like to
keep everything separate and in my own
folders
and so this is the way i do it to stay
organized if you copy it to the library
you can do that as well
but things seem to be a bit less
organized when i do that as far as
keywords go we can leave both of those
checked and then for analyze video i
like to leave both of these
unchecked for transcode under optimized
media if you have some weird file sizes
this is going to make it more compatible
with final cut pro by making it a pro
res file or you can create
proxy medias which is what i like to use
so if you have a slow computer
you can create a proxy media and
basically it's a low resolution
file size and so it's a lot smaller
files and they run a lot faster on your
computer
and then you can sub those out when you
start editing and then when you go to
export your final project
you basically replace your hi-res
whether it's 4k or just
even 1080 and then your final edit is
going to have those original files
back in place but it makes the editing
so much easier and so much faster
especially if you have a slow computer
so i'm going to select create proxy
media and for my
codec prores proxy is going to work fine
h.264 will work as well but i like to
use the prores proxies
frame size i'm going to leave at 50 and
after that we're just going to hit
import all
now we can see that we have footage
inside of final cut pro and up here we
have a loading bar so if we select this
this is actually going to show us the
background tasks that are happening
right now there is transcoding and
analysis that just means that it's
creating the proxy files for us if we
click this down
it's transcoding making the proxy clips
for each of these clips
right now now as that runs in the
background we can carry on now in order
to start editing
we need a project so events are kind of
what carries your music
your pictures your videos and your
project is your edit
it's where the videos and all the files
will go into you'll mess around with
them and that project is what you'll
export and again the library is what
holds
everything to create a new project we'll
go to file new
and select project for our project name
i'll just name it final cut
tutorial it's going to be in the event
fuji footage which is perfect for me and
for video i'm going to leave it at 4k
but if you shot in 1080 then hit 1080p
hd but for me mine is in 4k and this is
the correct resolution
for frame rate i actually shot in 23.98
frames per second
uh rendering codec all this stuff is
fine color space is fine
audio all that stuff you won't need to
touch from there you'll hit okay
and right up here you'll now see we have
a project also down here we can now move
this playhead because we have a project
and this is our project timeline this is
where we are going to edit
everything back up here in the events
where we have our videos you can see we
can
scrub through here and this is going to
allow us to view
this footage even before we add it to
our project if you scrub over your video
and hit the space bar this is actually
going to play it for you
so let's say all right this is the clip
i want to use you can either select it
once
and drag it into your timeline or
let me delete that now let's say you
just want to use the second half of this
clip you can actually
drag this and just bring down that
second half of the clip
or what you could do is just bring the
entire clip down
and trim it down here while it's already
in the timeline if you hold down shift
you can select
all your clips and just throw those in
the timeline and
edit it from there i do this a lot of
the time i just throw them all in
and then i start editing inside of my
project with some videos on the timeline
if you select one of these clips
over here we have our effect so if this
is not popping up yet
you can click this button right here and
that's going to bring up your effects
if you want to add a transition you can
actually click this one
and this is going to be your transitions
and it's as simple as dragging and
dropping so let's say we want to use
this cross dissolve i'll drag this over
the second clip
and right now it's going to say there's
not enough extra media just hit create
transition
and this is going to transition a cross
dissolve
between the two clips and if you want to
delete that you can just select your
transition and hit delete and that's
going to get rid of that transition
back over here on effects you can do the
same thing you can drag an effect right
here
and now you have a 50s tv effect and if
you want to delete an effect you can
select your clip
up here in the right hand corner this is
your properties right now at the top we
see effects
we can just select 50s tv and delete
that so
over here on the right hand side this is
all your information about your clip
or maybe your audio so you can see over
here we can mess with our opacity we can
change that
uh transform is like the positioning and
so you can move that around
you can also scale your image by
dragging the slider or you can
select the scale and maybe you want to
make it 200 you can do that as well now
what i like to do what i think is a lot
easier
is right down here we have this little
drop down menu you can do a transform
tool
and this is your scale right here you
can move the positioning
around you can scale it up or down you
know do whatever you want to do with
that
to reset this all you got to do is go
back up here and hit reset and that's
going to put everything back to normal
for your transform tool if we change
this to crop
this allows us to crop in on an image or
crop out on an image
and trim allows you to actually trim off
an image so if you want to make it more
of a square image
add something else in there you know you
can do that with trim another important
thing to look at on this viewer window
is this percentage right here so we have
the 70
if we want to make that 50 this actually
isn't changing the scale or anything
like that it's just changing the size
of it inside of our software so if i
want to make this as big as possible for
this window i would just hit
fit and that is going to fit it in here
so as
i move these around if i want to make
this bigger
this is just automatically going to make
it smaller for me or make it bigger if i
make the window bigger so to recap
down here is where we are going to edit
our project
up here is all of our videos so to
actually get these onto your project you
have to bring them down
into the timeline but this is where they
all are so if i delete some of these
they are still gonna be up here
they're not on the project or not on the
final video but it's not like i'm
deleting them out of the software
if i want to put them back in i can by
just dragging it back
onto the timeline over here we have our
event as well as our library and you can
create new events
if you want to maybe you have like a
part two or day two and you want to
separate the days
uh you could do that by just naming it
day two and then you have a brand new
event
so if you see no footage you might be on
the wrong event you need to go
to a different event where you have your
project you have your other footage but
this also allows you to organize things
inside of final cut if that makes it
easier for you typically i just keep
everything inside of one event so that's
the basics that's what you need to know
to kind of get started and get familiar
with final cut
if you want to learn how to start
editing for beginners then click on the
screen right now and i'll see you guys
in the next video
[Music]